<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Punctuation on I&#39;ve been left unattended: Tyler&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/punctuation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Punctuation on I&#39;ve been left unattended: Tyler&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/punctuation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Comma</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/comma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/comma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The comma is a ravenous mostly-deep-sea-but-sometimes-shallow-sea being in the world of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born in the late 1030s, the comma lived most of its early life under King Edward the Confessor. At that time, it was simply a line, or a mark. Sometimes people even called it Mark (never Marky, though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When things in the House of Wessex got, well, &lt;em&gt;just too crazy&lt;/em&gt;, the comma (Mark) got fed up, and a little peckish, and dove into the nearest body of water (perhaps &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solent&#34;&gt;the Solent&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short amount of time—a mere eight months—the comma became more fin-like, allowing it to glide through the water more easily. That change marked (or commaed) the end of a world where any text could just swim anywhere, now helpless against the comma&amp;rsquo;s superior speed, strength, and fed-upness. Note that text could still travel by sea, just not &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; the sea—the period got around just fine with its pirate ships, as you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the comma covers approximately 70% of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface (the idea that 70% of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface is covered by panthers is a common misconception). It still rises from the depths now and then to surge and stab at the pieces of text that dare drift into its territory, making them pause for a bit and sometimes even explain themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s all very inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slash</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/slash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/slash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The slash is a comfortable being in the world of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be obvious from the multitude of alternative names it possesses (&amp;ldquo;separatrix&amp;rdquo; suggests panther-grade malice, I tell you), but the slash/stroke/virgula suspensiva (actually that one might just be a species of panther) has a history rooted in equanimity, good cheer, and sweaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early (though some sources claim mid) 1500s, sweaters were increasing in popularity on an unprecedented scale. Sweatersmiths could barely keep up with the demand and had to make compromises, such as deintegrating doublets, virtually eliminating tri-cross-stitched versions, and using buttons instead of linchpins on the open-front models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of their construction, folks always slipped into these hip new cozy coverings with the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An upward tilt of one arm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A slick twist-and-slide move, the details of which are out of the scope of this list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A downward tip of the contralateral arm, with further fidgeting as required (usually necessary with sweaters that didn&amp;rsquo;t have buttons/linchpins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all this work, putting on a sweater required a substantially fit core, which led people to refer to this set of actions as &amp;ldquo;obliquing&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Longissimusing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;multifiding&amp;rdquo; were also in the running for a while. Over time, the shape one&amp;rsquo;s arms made during this whole process became known as the oblique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/img/stroke-gallego.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CAN YOU FEEL THE / IN YOU&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt; Demonstrated here by Sr. Gallego. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is sure how we got all these other names (except slak, that one&amp;rsquo;s obvious, thanks Wojkowice), but well, here we are and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice and warm, come on in. Have a cider or something and let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.*&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apostrophe</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/apostrophe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/apostrophe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The apostrophe is a high-flying being in the world of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the period is a snail, the apostrophe is a jet plane, and not something like those ridiculous Super Guppies, no, of course not, it&amp;rsquo;d probably be one of those private jets you would book based on how much you liked the shape of the windows, then as you watched the world underneath you&amp;rsquo;d wonder how you&amp;rsquo;d gotten there and start becoming disgusted at how high above the ground you were, chiding yourself oh-so-silently and just wanting to sit in a diner, any diner, yes I&amp;rsquo;ll take a pie and coffee, did you know they serve pie and coffee on planes, too, it isn&amp;rsquo;t as good though, ha, it&amp;rsquo;s never as good, it can&amp;rsquo;t be, up there where you can start to see the world as the speck it really is, the last thing you want is pie and coffee, you want something to remember, or maybe something to forget, or maybe just something to distract that vicious-looking panther a mere two rows behind you, but pie and coffee are none of those, and they never will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right. So the the apostrophe was created in the late 1800s, when seriously everyone wanted some piece of that flying-in-the-sky pie (sigh). It was originally supposed to look more like a tilde, but real-world tests quickly established that the style of apostrophe used today had the best power-to-weight ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was named the apostrophe in honor of the rhetorical figure of speech, as millions (or perhaps several more) dreamed of the mark turning away from all other bits on the page, pressing against the invisible ceiling that paper imposes on all its subjects. Could the apostrophe someday triumphantly shatter everything on the page around it and soar past you and your hair, streaks of ink finally fusing with the dusty, sun-warmed air to create that just-burst-out-of-the-book smell while leaping and climbing ever higher? It could. It &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; could. Be ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Period</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/period/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The period is a roguish being in the world of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lived with pirates! Oh my goodness. The period has strutted all around ship decks, sail compartments, and flag rooms - not that it only strutted. It&amp;rsquo;s seen ferocious battles against Redcoats, Bearded Redcoats, Antipirates, and other totally fearsome crews. Buccaneering? Check. Swashbuckling? Double Check. Multi-Cutlassing? Multi-Check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, however, the period did not get its name from some warped version of the word &amp;ldquo;pirate&amp;rdquo;, nor from &amp;ldquo;parrot&amp;rdquo;. These lies were started by vicious panthers, and don&amp;rsquo;t you dare spread them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The period was originally part of the entity known as the ellipsis, but then it got all restless and broke away to join up with the nice seafaring folks that were passing by, making the other part of the ellipsis so angry. People started calling this newly isolated (and seafaring) dot a &amp;ldquo;period&amp;rdquo; after coming up with some analogy where the ellipsis represented eternity. Kind of sloppy analogy work? Maybe. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The period is also known as a full stop, because it&amp;rsquo;s now used to fully end sentences, and a dot, because it&amp;rsquo;s a tiny round thing. These terms should hardly be surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is a mark with such a glorious history one of the smallest bits of language? First of all, being small gives it a tremendous radness-to-radius ratio. Mainly, though, the small-yet-potent mark was what the world needed at that exact moment. The time was right for the period to emerge from the ellipsis, to rise above the (grossly miscalculated) ideal dot distribution level, and to trigger a series of events that would grab the world by its pirate-snubbing nose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Caret</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/caret/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/caret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The caret is a practically nonexistent being in the world of punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caret is a long-stale relic of the circumflex, the mildly useful overstrike from a time lost. Who needs such a bendy thing these days? The caret has been ritually driven out by more practical alternatives. The youth of this world don&amp;rsquo;t even know what a caret is. It&amp;rsquo;s been covered up by its own uselessness to the point that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even know how to describe itself. Upward pointing? Pah. We have arrows for that. Shark fins and mountain ranges? It just can&amp;rsquo;t beat the real thing. Any merit the caret could have ever had in days past has been dissolved, and the caret can&amp;rsquo;t expect to stay harbored in its own shadowy waters and not suffocate. The caret is pointless (in spite of the pun). The caret is forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caret? The caret is dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what some would have you believe, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth? The caret isn&amp;rsquo;t an silly lifeform made up of organic compounds. It&amp;rsquo;s not destined to age and decompose - rather, it&amp;rsquo;s an idea that you and millions of people like you (and unlike you [and sort of like you, you know, maybe they have a similar personality but they&amp;rsquo;ve never been paralyzed by a panther&amp;rsquo;s vicious gaze, now have they?]) have breathed life into. No matter how rarely you use it when you text your pals, draft a grocery list, or revise your personal tagline, you may someday use it when you dabble in ASCII art. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t die unless you (and those other people, remember them?) want it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Semicolon</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/semicolon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/semicolon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The semicolon is a haunting being in the world of punctuation. Stuck between structural syntaxes from the start, the semicolon rides the no-man&amp;rsquo;s-land between sincere appreciation, filppant exploitation, and indifference. It&amp;rsquo;s less like a no-man&amp;rsquo;s land and more like the center of a Venn diagram, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You walk into its study and there isn&amp;rsquo;t a cloak in sight. It hates cloaks. It&amp;rsquo;s playing a modest-sized pipe organ, making a modest-sized tune that flips (modestly) between calming and nerve-wracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not going to scare you. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t created to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask it to pick out a cloak (because you brought a few of them and one might strike the semicolon&amp;rsquo;s fancy even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t normally like them, you know) and it extends two hands that you reach out to hold, and you can faintly feel them in yours — you look down despite a sinking feeling and a hesitant breath that your brain makes you take. Your trembling, incredulous, palms-up hands are all you see. Semicolons don&amp;rsquo;t have hands, fool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask it to describe itself, and it plays a new little melody on the grey and gold pipe organ (with&amp;hellip;with no hands?). When you close your eyes on the high note, it holds the note for a little too long, then lowers its head (semicolons do have heads), stands, and exits softly before your goosebumps can fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You look around and realize that you&amp;rsquo;re not a part of anything that this piece of punctuation is becoming — this has already started to happen and will happen with or without your use of the mark. A world with the semicolon in the wrong circle of the Venn diagram is a world no one should see, but it&amp;rsquo;s a world that could exist. The most you can do is to trust that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t swing to that circle, partially because merely imagining a future with a fallen semicolon gives you chills, and partially because panthers live there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eroteme</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/eroteme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/eroteme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question mark is a highly regarded being in the world of punctuation. Its curly-but-not-too-curly-and-also-there-is-a-dot-there nature gives it that aura of superior breeding that ampersands can only wish for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, things weren’t always so easy for the question mark. It made its first appearance in the Shetland Isles, where it was created and raised to pull carts and plow farmland. It was a mutually beneficial relationship, as carts and farmland were pretty much everywhere at that time, and the question mark got free food, shelter, and protection from panthers. Then the Shetland Pony came around and botched that all up, didn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait a—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I…Can we use it for sen—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guys, listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we use it for sentences like that one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or that one?…Or this one??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that point on, the new use of the question mark was obvious. Or was it? Well, well! There’s another use! Doubt is always a fun bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this discovery, the question mark still had some opposition. People were uncomfortable asking questions (and statements of uncertainty?) in a written manner, it gave everyone one more dot to dot, and all the silly kids were annoying all the mature individuals by making that “mmmMMM?” noise whenever they wrote the mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all changed (of course?) with the invention of the keyboard, where the question mark was paired up with the slash. Folks back then figured they’d put the slash as far away from the escape key as possible, because they didn’t want any chance of an action movie being named Slash Escape. The question mark had convinced the slash that it would never be called Backslash again if they teamed up. The question mark really had no solid plan to put this in place, but it had the best of intentions. Something about “If you’re questioning whether to look back, then it’s probably not a good idea, and the furthest right is what is also in the back, and maybe you should pipe down [it was in this general area that the question mark kept getting distracted by the WASD revolution taking place, and this whole slogan really didn&amp;rsquo;t get much farther]…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all this, the question mark and slash ended up being right next to the shift key. Slippery keyboards were (probably, we really don’t know) a huge fad back then, and the question mark was accidentally typed quite often. Typists were soon thinking, “Oops…hm…yeah…yeah, that could be a question. Yeah. Why not? Ha, that was also a question.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the question mark is all over the place, an essential part of our doubt, curiosity, double takes, feedback, tests, slogans, and it’s also a delicious part of our concluding sentences as well, isn’t it? Sometimes it is. Sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bang</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/bang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The exclamation mark? I&amp;hellip;whatever. It&amp;rsquo;s probably some kind of specter in the world of punctuation? Something mysterious. Not that it makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s silly. Let&amp;rsquo;s just get that out of the way right now. What in the world is it for? Nothing. The world is written in questions (isn&amp;rsquo;t it?), not shrieks and battle cries. The exclamation mark is a renegade, trying to force its way into conversations where it isn&amp;rsquo;t even wanted. The exclamation mark fights with overly large plastic knives when it should have retreated to the corner long ago and just patiently waited to be written over in a hurried manner as, maybe, I don&amp;rsquo;t know, some kind of h or something, how else would the word bokeh even be around, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exclamation mark is not a professional. It can&amp;rsquo;t be. Origins on the beach? Seen by a foolish few as a mark that would signal the &amp;ldquo;revitalization of punctuation&amp;rdquo;? As delightfully harmonious as that phrase is, the exclamation mark fell into the position it is in now because some small child needed to scribble something in the sand to distract the fast approaching sand panthers. Kid could&amp;rsquo;ve drawn about anything with the same result. Why a line and a dot? Because it&amp;rsquo;s easy. Because it&amp;rsquo;s cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m getting excited about this whole matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not even a matter. It&amp;rsquo;s hardly whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care that it&amp;rsquo;s useful in number theory (zero factorial is one? All right, that&amp;rsquo;s not bad). I don&amp;rsquo;t care that it can signify a logical negation. Is there such a thing as a factorial of a negation of a remark about your sleeves that was screamed from across the street by a chili vendor? No&amp;hellip;What? No, of course there isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t any such thing because it was never meant to be. The exclamation mark has no place here. Has everyone been waiting for a love story between the exclamation mark and, what, the slash, guys? No. Can I say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; any more emphatically? YES. YES I CAN. EMPHASIS OBTAINED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: The author continued to use caps lock in a highly uncivilized manner in the paragraphs that followed (and sheesh, there were so many). These have been retracted as it was not cool (also, sheesh, so many). The views and opinions of the author are not our own and do not represent our attitude towards just about anything? That should cover it, right? I&amp;rsquo;m not the one being attacked by sand panthers from the future.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hyphen</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/hyphen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/hyphen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hyphen is serious business in the world of punctuation. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t even&amp;hellip;you don&amp;rsquo;t even know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hyphen is one of the earliest forms of punctuation, due to the fact that it is half of an equals sign, which is also one of the earliest forms of punctuation, due to the fact that assignment operators weren&amp;rsquo;t going to just create themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyphens were officially recognized as punctuation in the early 12th century, when John II Komnenos was writing up a sweet script to automatically correct any spelling errors in the word &amp;ldquo;Pecheneg&amp;rdquo; when, as the story goes, he was attacked by a vicious beast (likely a panther) and only placed half of the equality symbol on the piece of paper. Liking the way it looked, he kept it, and no one could do much about it, except deridingly mention that the other line must have escaped while it had the chance, but those people hated the future anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hyphen has branched out so many ways in an effort to create more delicious varieties for itself. What first started out as a pinch of minor stretches and shifts has now become a glut of twists and measurements, overly redundant nomenclature for the sake of a thickness no one can agree upon, beating you down, masked with simplicity but wielding a cane-sword inside fifteen other cane-swords, but then striking at your mind with a regular cane, just to confuse you even more. It also has trust issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the hyphen is Vanilla (word-joining Vanilla), then here are some other flavors filled with goodness (sometimes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The en dash (–), which is about the width of an &amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo;, is what should REALLY be used for ranges and some other things like compound adjectives for which neither part of the adjective modifies the other; that is, when each is modifying the noun&amp;hellip;yeah, you know. It&amp;rsquo;s the French Vanilla of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The em dash (—) is about the width of the letter m, and is used for parenthetical examples—parenthetical example witticism here—and for any kind of interruption in speech. It&amp;rsquo;s the Cookies &amp;amp; Cream, and is almost as yummy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The horizontal bar is (―) is like Cookies &amp;amp; Cream with sprinkles. It&amp;rsquo;s also used as an anti-caking agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The swung dash (⁓) indicates the extension of a vowel in Japanese, and wears a baseball cap everywhere it goes. Black Cherry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tilde (~) is Low-Fat Black Cherry, and that&amp;rsquo;s all it can say right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underscore (_) is either a diacritic mark or a character replacing a standard space, but no one knows for sure. It is Chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The macron (¯) is WAAAY up there! Look at it! Isn&amp;rsquo;t that just gorgeous? Research has shown similarities to Rocky Road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hyphen bullet (⁃) is a short horizontal line. What? Oh, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s Butter Pecan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minus sign (−) is used in math once in a while. It has quite a life of its own. Mint Chocolate Chip. In a waffle cone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wave dash (〜) is too silly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hebrew maqaf (־) has been focusing on some previously neglected life goals. It recently announced that it plans to maintain its Strawberry status, and there was much rejoicing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mongolian todo hyphen (᠆) is from the Mongolian alphabet, which has a few characters that might look a little like horsies. Superman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hangul Jungseong Eu (ᅳ) sometimes sneaks into em dash&amp;rsquo;s stuff but then puts it back and no one knows. Orange Sherbet seems likely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Japanese chōonpu (ー) is also known as &amp;ldquo;that flying carpet one.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s Rainbow Sherbet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Chinese character for &amp;ldquo;one&amp;rdquo; (一) is pretty close to a sideways &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;. Many compare this to Chocolate Chip Cookie Dough, unjustly, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ampersand</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/ampersand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/ampersand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ampersand is a pretty crazy looking little guy. It is used to join all kinds of words and numbers and even just plain old letters together. Where would the letters M, B, R, or even D be without the ampersand? In a much better place, that&amp;rsquo;s where. I&amp;rsquo;m here to tell you about the dangers of the ampersand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born to a family of bloodthirsty (and almost impossibly agile) panthers, the ampersand lived a life of shadows and squiggliness. Never to be content with its life of power, glory, and agility, it forged itself into a new being, a punctuation mark. The skies swirled ominously that day, although it was windy the rest of that week too, so whatever, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. In the midst of the first century, the very day Vindex revolted, the ampersand started a new life. A life in which it would reign absolute terror over all it surveyed. A life from which it was impossible to escape, sort of like when the tongue of your shoe gets tucked down inside itself. A life of agility, still, though, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ampersand grew in squiggliness and malevolence throughout the centuries, devouring lowercase letters at first, but not stopping there, never stopping, its vicious serifs snapping letters, numbers, words, and eventually lifeboats into itsy-bitsy little pieces. As the printing press, typewriters, and computerized text all evolved and grew in popularity (all of which were invented by the ampersand, actually, or maybe some of its college buddies) the ampersand was able to cover the world with the dark, dripping substance which is evil in the form of a dark, dripping substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the ampersand has more coverage than ever, and it uses this towards its nefarious goal of connecting everyone everywhere at the same time for eternity. Swirling and squiggling around in the nonexistent neverness that is time, stretching the connections, bridging our hopes and dreams with its frigid, bottomless glare. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what it wants. Squish it. Squish it on your keyboard right now. Tell it to suffocate on your warm human finger. Give it the evil eye. Frown at it disappointedly. Whatever. Just show it who is boss. You.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up. Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though. You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Asterisk</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/asterisk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The asterisk is an elusive being in the world of punctuation.
It is most often used in texts such as books, articles, and Web Logs (commonly shortened to &amp;ldquo;blogs&amp;rdquo;) to distract you from the issue at hand* and give you something to look forward to;
if one shows up, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that there may be more lying in wait. Like vicious panthers.
Panthers of distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The asterisk originated in the late 1700s by Captain James Cook, who,
upon mapping the eastern coast of the Australian continent,
was driven mad by the sight of a small herd of echidnas,
drawing the little blighters in all his reports from that point on.
This is why the asterisk is also used as a &amp;ldquo;wild card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was loved by the general public; upon reading all his reports on his livejournal
(a paper-based system at the time)
the mark spread rapidly as a way of making little side notes,
mainly because they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any punctuation for that sort of thing at the time,
and this seemed good enough.
Giving the critters eyes seemed a little creepy, though, so they just went with five or six points, or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;asterisk&amp;rdquo; itself was coined because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything separating asterion and astern in the dictionary yet,
and people in med school simply DETESTED being associated in any way with those vulgar sailing folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* 10²+ 11² + 12² = 13² + 14²&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org/tags/punctuation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up.
Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though.
You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>