<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ASTERISK</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/asterisk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The asterisk is an elusive being in the world of punctuation.
It is most often used in texts such as books, articles, and Web Logs (commonly shortened to &amp;ldquo;blogs&amp;rdquo;) to distract you from the issue at hand* and give you something to look forward to;
if one shows up, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that there may be more lying in wait. Like vicious panthers.
Panthers of distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The asterisk originated in the late 1700s by Captain James Cook, who,
upon mapping the eastern coast of the Australian continent,
was driven mad by the sight of a small herd of echidnas,
drawing the little blighters in all his reports from that point on.
This is why the asterisk is also used as a &amp;ldquo;wild card&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was loved by the general public; upon reading all his reports on his livejournal
(a paper-based system at the time)
the mark spread rapidly as a way of making little side notes,
mainly because they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any punctuation for that sort of thing at the time,
and this seemed good enough.
Giving the critters eyes seemed a little creepy, though, so they just went with five or six points, or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;asterisk&amp;rdquo; itself was coined because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything seperating asterion and astern in the dictionary yet,
and people in med school simply DETESTED being associated in any way with those vulgar sailing folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on &lt;strong&gt;punctuation&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all made up.
Don&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the prowess of a panther, though.
You&amp;rsquo;ve been warned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* 10²+ 11² + 12² = 13² + 14²&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/post/first/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-post&#34;&gt;First post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello world&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>